I am passionate about the American landscape
أنا متحمسة حول الأراضي الامريكية الأميركي
and how the physical form of the land,
وكيف الشكل المادي للأرض،
from the great Central Valley of California
من الوادي الوسطى الكبير في كاليفورنيا
to the bedrock of Manhattan,
والأساس الذي تقوم عليه مانهاتن،
has really shaped our history and our character.
شكل حقا تاريخنا وشخصيتنا.
But one thing is clear.
ولكن هناك شيء واضح.
In the last 100 years alone,
في السنوات ال 100 الماضية وحدها،
our country -- and this is a sprawl map of America --
بلادنا -- وهذا هو امتداد للخريطة الأمريكية --
our country has systematically
بلدنا بشكل منهجي
flattened and homogenized the landscape
ارض مسطحة متجانسة
to the point where we've forgotten
إلى النقطة التي نسينا فيها
our relationship with the plants and animals
علاقتنا مع النباتات والحيوانات
that live alongside us
التي تعيش حولنا
and the dirt beneath our feet.
والاوساخ تحت أقدامنا.
And so, how I see my work contributing
وكيف أرى عملي انه مساهمة
is sort of trying to literally re-imagine these connections
من نوع محاولة "حرفيا" إعادة تخيل هذه الاتصالات
and physically rebuild them.
واعادة بنائها فيزيائيا
This graph represents what we're dealing with now
هذا الرسم البياني يمثل ما نتعامل معه الآن
in the built environment.
في البيئة المبنية.
And it's really a conflux
وانها حقا معقدة
of urban population rising,
من حيث الارتفاع في النمو السكاني
biodiversity plummeting
فتراجع التنوع البيولوجي
and also, of course, sea levels rising
وأيضا ، بطبيعة الحال، ارتفاع مستويات سطح البحر
and climate changing.
وتغيير المناخ
So when I also think about design,
حتى عندما أفكر أيضا حول التصميم،
I think about
افكر حول
trying to rework and re-engage
محاولة لإعادة صياغة واعادة العلاقات
the lines on this graph
خطوط هذا الرسم البياني
in a more productive way.
بطريقة أكثر إنتاجية.
And you can see from the arrow here
ويمكنك ان ترى السهم من هنا
indicating "you are here,"
يري اننا هنا
I'm trying to sort of blend and meld
أحاول أن افرز من المزج وأخلط
these two very divergent fields
ان هذه مجالات مختلفة تماما
of urbanism and ecology,
من التمدن والبيئة،
and sort of bring them together in an exciting new way.
ونوع من جمعهم معا في طريقة جديدة مثيرة.
So the era of big infrastructure is over.
حتى عهد البنية التحتية الكبيرة قد انتهى.
I mean, these sort of top-down,
أعني، هذا النوع من من بنائية "أعلى إلى أسفل" ،
mono-functional, capital-intensive solutions
أحادية الفنية، والحلول كثيفة رأس المال...
are really not going to cut it.
حقيقة لن نستطيع ايقافها
We need new tools and new approaches.
نحن بحاجة إلى أدوات جديدة ومناهج جديدة.
Similarly, the idea of architecture
مثل، فكرة الهندسة المعمارية
as this sort of object in the field,
وهذا النوع من الكائن في الميدان ،
devoid of context,
خالية من السياق،
is really not the --
حقيقة ليس هو
excuse me, it's fairly blatant --
إسمح لي، انها صارخ إلى حد ما --
is really not the approach
في الحقيقة ليست النهج
that we need to take.
الذي نحتاج ان ننتهجه
So we need new stories,
لذلك نحتاج قصصا جديدة
new heroes and new tools.
ادوات وابطال جدد
So now I want to introduce you to my new hero
حتى الآن أريد أن أعرض لكم بطلي الجديد
in the global climate change war,
في الحرب لتغير المناخ العالمي ،
and that is the eastern oyster.
وهذا هو المحار الشرقي.
So, albeit a very small creature
بذلك ، وإن كان مخلوق صغير جدا
and very modest,
ومتواضع جدا،
this creature is incredible,
هذا المخلوق لا يصدق،
because it can agglomerate
لأنه يمكن أن يكتل
into these mega-reef structures.
في هذه الهياكل الضخمة المرجانية،
It can grow; you can grow it;
ويمكن أن تنمو، أي يمكنك ان تنميه ،
and -- did I mention? -- it's quite tasty.
وأنا لم أذكر، إنه لذيذ جدا.
So the oyster was the basis
هكذا كان المحار أساس
for a manifesto-like urban design project
عرض مشروع التصميم المدني
that I did about the New York Harbor
الذي قمت به في ميناء نيويورك
called "oyster-tecture."
ويسمي "المحار، الملمس."
And the core idea of oyster-tecture is to harness the biological power
والفكرة الأساسية من المحار هو تسخير الطاقة البيولوجية
of mussels, eelgrass and oysters --
من بلح البحر، عشب ثعبان البحر والمحار --
species that live in the harbor --
الأنواع التي تعيش في الميناء --
and, at the same time,
وفي الوقت نفسه،
harness the power of people
تسخير قوة الشعب
who live in the community
الذين يعيشون في المجتمع
towards making change now.
نحو إحداث التغيير الآن.
Here's a map of my city, New York City,
وفيما يلي خريطة لمدينتي، مدينة نيويورك ،
showing inundation in red.
مع عرض غمر باللون الأحمر.
And what's circled is the site that I'm going to talk about,
وعينت ما هو الموقع الذي انا ذاهبة الى الحديث عن،
the Gowanus Canal and Governors Island.
قناة جوانوس .. وجزيرة الحكماء
If you look here at this map,
اذا نظرتم الى هنا في هذه الخريطة،
showing everything in blue
التي تعرض كل شئ باللون الأزرق
is out in the water,
و هو خارج الماء
and everything in yellow is upland.
واي شئ اصفر هو اليابسة
But you can see, even just intuit, from this map,
ولكن يمكنك أن ترى، حتى يستشعر فقط من هذه الخريطة،
that the harbor has dredged and flattened,
التي تم حفر الميناء بالارض ،
and went from a rich, three-dimensional mosaic to flat muck
وتحول من فسيفساء غنية ثلاثية الأبعاد لمسطح طيني
in really a matter of years.
في سنوات قليلة
Another set of views of actually the Gowanus Canal itself.
ومشهد اخر هو مشهد القناة نفسها
Now the Gowanus is particularly smelly -- I will admit it.
الان رائحتها لا توصف سأتجاوز هذا
There are problems of sewage overflow
هناك مشكلات من تجاوز الصرف الصحي
and contamination,
والتلوث،
but I would also argue that almost every city
ولكن أود أن أقول أيضا أن ما يقرب من كل مدينة
has this exact condition,
لديها نفس الوضع
and it's a condition that we're all facing.
وانه وضع نواجهه كلنا
And here's a map of that condition,
وهذه خريطة للوضع
showing the contaminants in yellow and green,
موضحة التلوث بالإخضر والأصفر
exacerbated by this new flow of
تتفاقم بفعل هذا التدفق الجديد
storm-surge and sea-level rise.
العواصف وارتفاع مستوى سطح البحر.
So we really had a lot to deal with.
لذلك كان علينا حقا الكثير للتعامل معها.
When we started this project,
عندما بدأنا هذا المشروع ،
one of the core ideas was to look back in history
واحدة من الأفكار الأساسية ما أن ننظر إلى الوراء في التاريخ
and try to understand what was there.
ومحاولة فهم ما كان هناك.
And you can see from this map,
ويمكنك أن ترى من هذه الخريطة،
there's this incredible geographical signature
هذا التوقيع الجغرافي المدهش
of a series of islands
من سلسلة من الجزر
that were out in the harbor
التي كانت في المرفأ
and a matrix of salt marshes and beaches
ومصفوفة من المستنقعات المالحة والشواطئ
that served as natural wave attenuation
التي خدمت تضعيف موجة الطبيعة
for the upland settlement.
لتسوية المرتفعات.
We also learned at this time
وعلمنا أيضا في هذا الوقت
that you could eat an oyster about the size of a dinner plate
هل يمكن أن يأكل المحار في حجم طبق عشاء
in the Gowanus Canal itself.
في القناة نفسها
So our concept is really this back-to-the-future concept,
فمفهومنا هو حقا هذا المفهوم هو العودة إلى المستقبل،
harnessing the intelligence of that land settlement pattern.
تسخير الاستخبارات من أجل تسوية نمط الأرض
And the idea has two core stages.
والفكرة الأساسية لها مرحلتان
One is to develop a new artificial ecology,
واحد هو تطوير علم البيئة الجديدة المصطنعة،
a reef out in the harbor,
للخروج الشعب المرجانية في الميناء،
that would then protect new settlement patterns
ومن شأن ذلك حماية انماط حياة ومن .ثم مستوطنة جديدة
inland and the Gowanus.
جزيرة القوان
Because if you have cleaner water and slower water,
لأنه ان كان لديك مياه نظيفة وبطيئة
you can imagine a new way of living with that water.
يمكنك أن تتخيل طريقة جديدة للعيش مع هذه المياه.
So the project really addresses these three core issues
بحيث يعالج المشروع حقا هذه القضايا الثلاث الأساسية
in a new and exciting way, I think.
في طريقة جديدة ومثيرة، وأعتقد.
Here we are, back to our hero, the oyster.
نحن هنا، مرة أخرى إلى بطلنا المحار.
And again, it's this incredibly exciting animal.
ومرة أخرى ، فإن هذا الحيوان مثير بشكل لا يصدق.
It accepts algae and detritus in one end,
أنه يقبل الطحالب والمخلفات من جهة ،
and through this beautiful, glamorous
ومن خلال 'طريقة جميلة، براقة
set of stomach organs,
مجموعة من الأجهزة المعدة،
out the other end comes cleaner water.
من الطرف الآخر تأتي المياه النظيفة
And one oyster can filter up to 50 gallons of water a day.
ويمكن للمحار تصفية ما يصل الى 50 غالون من الماء يوميا.
Oyster reefs also covered
كما غط المحار الأرصفة
about a quarter of our harbor
حوالي ربع مرفأنا
and were capable of filtering water in the harbor in a matter of days.
وكانت قادرة على تصفية الماء في الميناء في غضون أيام.
They were key in our culture and our economy.
وكانو هناك سبب رئيسي في ثقافتنا واقتصادنا.
Basically, New York was built
أساسا، نيويورك بنيت
on the backs of oystermen,
على أكتاف المحار
and our streets were literally built over oyster shells.
وبنيت حرفيا شوارعنا أكثر من اصداف المحار.
This image
هذه الصورة
is an image of an oyster cart,
هو صورة من بطاقة المحار،
which is now as ubiquitous as the hotdog cart is today.
التي هي الآن في كل مكان مثل عربة الهوت دوغ عليه اليوم.
So again, we got the short end of the deal there.
هذه هي صفقتنا اليوم .. لقد كنا جزء من اللعبة
(Laughter)
ضحك
Finally, oysters can attenuate
وأخيرا، يمكن أن تخفف من المحار
and agglomerate onto each other
وتتكتل على بعضها البعض
and form these amazing natural reef structures.
وتشكل هذه الهياكل المرجانية الطبيعية المدهشة.
They really become nature's wave attenuators.
تصبح حقا مخففات أمواج طبيعة.
And they become the bedrock
وتصبح حجر الأساس
of any harbor ecosystem.
من أي نظام إيكولوجي في الميناء.
Many, many species depend on them.
كثير من أنواع كثيرة من المخلوقات تعتمد عليها.
So we were inspired by the oyster,
هكذا كانت نستلهم من المحار،
but I was also inspired by the life cycle of the oyster.
ولكن أنا أيضا كنت مستلهمة من دورة حياة المحار.
It can move from a fertilized egg
ويمكن أن تنتقل من البويضة المخصبة
to a spat, which is when they're floating through the water,
إلى خلافه، وهو عندما تكون عائمة في المياه،
and when they're ready to attach onto another oyster,
وعندما تكون مستعدة لتتعلق على محار آخر
to an adult male oyster or female oyster,
إلى المحار الذكور البالغين أو المحار الأنثى
in a number of weeks.
في عدد من الأسابيع
We reinterpreted this life cycle
نحن أعدنا تفسير دورة الحياة هذه
on the scale of our sight
من منظورنا نحن
and took the Gowanus
وأخذ من القوناس
as a giant oyster nursery
كما أن دار حضانة المحار العملاق
where oysters would be grown up in the Gowanus,
حيث يكبر المحار في القنوات
then paraded down in their spat stage
ثم تتنظم بصورة اخرى
and seeded out on the Bayridge Reef.
وتتنظم علي هذه الجسور
And so the core idea here
عليه الفكرة الأساسية هنا
was to hit the reset button
كانت اعادة تدوير الحياة
and regenerate an ecology over time
وتجديد الإيكولوجية على مر الزمن
that was regenerative and cleaning
وكان هذا التجدد والتنظيف
and productive.
والإنتاج
How does the reef work? Well, it's very, very simple.
كيف تعمل الشعاب المرجانية؟ حسنا ، انها بسيطة جدا جدا.
A core concept here
المفهوم الأساسي هنا هو
is that climate change
تغير المناخ
isn't something that --
ليس شيئا يمكن
the answers won't land down from the Moon.
ان الأجوبة تنزل من القمر
And with a $20 billion price tag,
وعليها رقم 20 مليون دولار
we should simply start and get to work with what we have now
علينا ببساطة ان نبدأ بالعمل بما لدينا الان
and what's in front of us.
وماهو أمامنا
So this image is simply showing --
ببساطة الصور تري ان
it's a field of marine piles
انها ميدان من أكوام البحرية
interconnected with this woven fuzzy rope.
مترابطة مع هذا الحبل غامض النسج
What is fuzzy rope, you ask?
ماهو هذا النسج الغامض قد تسألون؟
It's just that; it's this very inexpensive thing,
انها مجرد ذلك ، بل هذا شيء غير مكلف للغاية،
available practically at your hardware store, and it's very cheap.
المتاحة عمليا في متجر لاجهزة الكمبيوتر الخاص بك ، وانها رخيصة جدا.
So we imagine that we would actually
لذلك نحن نتصور أننا في الواقع
potentially even host a bake sale
يحتمل أن تكون مضافة في مكان بيع الخبز
to start our new project.
لنبدا مشروع جديد
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So in the studio, rather than drawing,
حتى في الاستوديو ، وبدلا من الرسم.
we began to learn how to knit.
بدأنا نتعلم كيفية تماسكها
The concept was to really knit this rope together
وكان لمفهوم الترابط حقا هذا الحبل الرابط
and develop this new soft infrastructure
وتطوير هذه البنية التحتية الجديدة اللينة
for the oysters to grow on.
للمحار لكي تنمو عليه
You can see in the diagram how it grows over time
يمكنك ان ترى في الرسم التخطيطي كيف ينمو على مر الزمن
from an infrastructural space
من مساحة البنية التحتية
into a new public urban space.
الي فضاء المساحة العامة
And that grows over time dynamically
والذي ينمو بطريقة حيوية علي مر الزمن
with the threat of climate change.
مع تهديد تغير المناخ.
It also creates this incredibly interesting, I think,
فهي تخلق هذا الشئ الرائع
new amphibious public space,
برمائيات في المساحات الشاسعة
where you can imagine working,
حيث يمكنك أن تتخيل العمل،
you can imagine recreating in a new way.
يمكنك أن تتخيل إعادة الصياغة بطريقة جديدة.
In the end, what we realized we were making
في النهاية، ما أدركنا أننا كنا نصنع
was a new blue-green watery park
كانت حديقة مائية جديدة بالأخضر والأزرق
for the next watery century --
للقرن المقبل المائي --
an amphibious park, if you will.
وحديقة للبرمائيات ويمكنك
So get your Tevas on.
حيث تحصل علي حديقتك الخاصة
So you can imagine scuba diving here.
ويمكنك ان تتخيل السباحة هنا
This is an image of high school students,
هذه هي صورة من طلاب المدارس الثانوية،
scuba divers that we worked with on our team.
غواصين عملنا معهم في فريقنا.
So you can imagine a sort of new manner of living
بحيث يمكنك أن تتخيل نوع من طريقة جديدة للعيش
with a new relationship with the water,
مع علاقة جديدة مع الماء،
and also a hybridizing of recreational and science programs
وكذلك التهجين من البرامج الترفيهية والعلوم
in terms of monitoring.
من حيث الرصد.
Another new vocabulary word for the brave new world:
آخر كلمة جديدة لمفردات العالم الجديد الشجاع :
this is the word "flupsy" --
كلمة فلسبي
it's short for "floating upwelling system."
انها اختصار لتعويم نظام الموجات المتقلبة.
And this glorious, readily available device
وهذا جهاز متاح
is basically a floating raft
هي في الأساس مجموعة كبيرة عائمة
with an oyster nursery below.
مع حضانة المحار أدناه.
So the water is churned through this raft.
بحيث يتم خلط المياه من خلال هذه الطوافة.
You can see the eight chambers on the side
يمكنك ان ترى الدوائر ثمانية على الجانب
host little baby oysters and essentially force-feed them.
المحار المضيف الطفل ، و إطعامهم بالقوة.
So rather than having 10 oysters,
لذا بدلا من وجود 10 من المحار،
you have 10,000 oysters.
لديك 10000 المحار.
And then those spat are then seeded.
ثم تغذية هؤلاء جميعهم
Here's the Gowanus future
هذا هو مستقبل القناة
with the oyster rafts on the shorelines --
مع طوافات المحار على الشواطئ --
the flupsification of the Gowanus.
وستكون فلسبة القناة
New word.
لعالم جديد
And also showing oyster gardening for the community
وعرض أيضا بستنة مجتمع المحار
along its edges.
على طول أطرافها.
And finally, how much fun it would be
وأخيرا، كم سيكون من المتعة
to watch the flupsy parade
مشاهدة الكوكب المفسلب
and cheer on the oyster spats
ونهتف لتكتلات المحار
as they go down to the reef.
لأنها تذهب الى الشعاب المرجانية.
I get asked two questions about this project.
أحصل على اثنين من الأسئلة حول هذا المشروع.
One is: why isn't it happening now?
واحد هو، لماذا لا يحدث الآن؟
And the second one is: when can we eat the oysters?
والثاني هو واحد، متى يمكننا أكل المحار؟
And the answer is: not yet, they're working.
والجواب هو، وليس بعد، انهم يعملون.
But we imagine, with our calculations,
لكننا نتصور، مع حساباتنا،
that by 2050,
بالعام 2050
you might be able to sink your teeth into a Gowanus oyster.
قد تتمكن من ذلك
To conclude, this is just one cross-section
وختاما ، هذا هو واحد فقط المقطع العرضي
of one piece of city,
من قطعة واحدة من المدينة،
but my dream is, my hope is,
لكن حلمي هو، وأملي هو،
that when you all go back to your own cities
أنه عندما تذهب كل مرة إلى المدن الخاصة بك
that we can start to work together and collaborate
يمكن أن نبدأ في العمل معا والتعاون
on remaking and reforming
على إعادة بناء وإصلاح
a new urban landscape
المشهد العمرانية الجديدة
towards a more sustainable, a more livable
نحو أكثر استدامة و، وأكثر ملاءمة للعيش فيها
and a more delicious future.
ومستقبل أكثر لذة في المذاق
Thank you.
شكرا لكم
(Applause)
تصفيق